## \_\_\_ IAN REYNOLDS .\_\_

## CONTACT

07832345129

★ teamian27@gmail.com

#### **PROFILE**

I am a motivated and enthusiastic individual looking for my next role. Due to my previous experience in education, management, retail, and customer services. I feel that a role within this area would suit my qualifications and ambitions. I also feel that my reliability, personality and "can do" attitude would fit well into this career. I am looking for a position that will challenge me and provide a stable and reliable income to support myself and family for many years to come.

For the past six years I have worked as a TEFL teacher in Spain, the UK and online. This has enabled me to hone my organisational, time management and customer service skills. I have also gained lots of experience working to deadlines, due to preparing students for exams. Prior to this I was Assistant Branch Manager at Travis Perkins. This job was customer centric and high pressured, I had to work to targets whilst simultaneously maintaining organisation and administrative duties. I have worked extensively in stock control during my time at Travis Perkins, I would do daily stock checks, organise the shop displays, prepare and participate in stocktakes, and manage invoices from our suppliers. I am efficient in Microsoft Office and have no problem adapting or learning new software systems.

As a person, I am reliable and put my all into everything I do. I am a family man; I have been married since 2011 and I have a fouryear-old daughter. When I am not spending time with my family I enjoy watching and playing football with my family and friends. I am also a movie enthusiast; I love watching

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Multiheat Services LTD – Procurement Manager

February 2022 - Present

Working within a busy office environment. Responsible for procurement and stock control within the company. This includes networking with suppliers to reduce costs and ensuring delivery efficiency. Also responsible for delivering customer quotes and resolving customer queries whilst making sure that sales targets are met.

#### **Covid 19 Track and Trace**

September 2021 - February 2022

I am currently working as a Mobile Service Operator (MSO) for Track and Trace. My role includes handing out, explaining, and collecting test kits from service users, setting up and closing the site daily and travelling between multiple sites throughout South Wales. The job is customer facing, fast paced, requires lots of flexibility and involves several procedures to do this job safely and effectively.

## **Self Employed English Teacher**

September 2018 - September 2019 & March 2020 - Present

I currently teach mixed nationality group classes of up to 5 students, this has given me a huge sense of cultural sensitivity and understanding of different cultures. Being self-employed has enabled to become more efficient in my administrative duties, as I must deal with my own financial accounts, plan lessons, give written feedback and teach students. To be an efficient teacher you have to have excellent communication, be adept at giving complex explanations and to also have fantastic customer service skills. Although, I enjoy this role, I am looking for a permanent, full-time career in which I can develop further.

## Bridge It English Cartagena – Teacher

September 2019 - March 2020

Although I only had the opportunity to work for this school for a short period of time, I had to leave this job because of COVID-19, my time here was a valuable experience. My duties here were teaching and preparing students for exams, ensuring that students were improving and keeping up with administration.

## **Star English Murcia - Teacher**

September 2017 - June 2018

Same role as above.

## **ELAC Study Vacations**

Due to the long summer holidays in Spain, I gained employment with ELAC which is a summer school for international students from all over the world. and discussing movies with friends and family. I love travelling to new places and meeting new people, one of my proudest achievements was in 2017, when I had the opportunity to travel to Israel to do volunteer teaching to underprivileged teenagers.

## **EDUCATION**

## University of South Wales

2001 - 2006

Media and Communication Studies (BA hons)

## Coleg Morganwg

2007 - 2009

**Business and Management Studies HND** 

#### IMI Granada

2015

**CELTA** teaching Certificate

## Cardiff & Vale College

July 2022 - Present

Level 5 Diploma in Web Application Development

## **SKILLS**

- Computer literate, knowledge of Microsoft office programs, in particular Word, Excel and PowerPoint.
- Full clean UK driving license.
- Experience of working with other cultures and non-English speakers.
- Excellent interpersonal skills.
- Highly reliable and adaptable.
- Open to further study.
- A very strong work ethic.
- Currently attending Welsh classes

It was a challenging but extremely rewarding role for many reasons, classes could sometimes have students from ages eleven to eighteen and up to seven different nationalities. However, there were many new skills gained during this fast-paced environment.

- o 2015 Teacher, Bath Spa University and Bath Priory Park
- o 2016 Teacher, Cardiff Met University
- o 2017 Academic Manager, Bath Spa University
  - Due to my highly rated performance over the previous two years, I was promoted to Academic Manager. It was a great chance to reuse my management skills. I was responsible for a team of ten teachers and I had to timetable classes for two hundred students at a time based on level and age. I also had to create a curriculum for the teachers to follow that would incorporate excursions and activities whilst still focusing on academic content and enjoyment.
- 2018 Assistant Centre Manager, Bath Spa University
  - o As a result of my work as Academic Manager, I was again promoted, this time to Assistant Centre Manager. This role required a huge amount multi-tasking. I dealt with student welfare, organisation of excursions, mentoring my replacement Academic Manager and liaising with the group leaders (the adults who accompanied the students) about all issues. It was a challenging role that involved being on call for the whole of the course. Due the age of the students, health and safety was paramount, I was responsible for conducting risk assessments every day or as and when the environment changed.
- o 2017 Volunteer teaching for ELAC charity in Nazareth, Israel
  - This was an amazing experience that I will never forget.
    For three weeks I was part of a team of volunteer teachers who taught a summer school for underprivileged students as part of the ELAC Education Trust.

## ECI Andujar - Teacher

September 2014 – June 2017 Same role as above.

# **Travis Perkins Building Merchants – Assistant Branch Manager**

August 2007 - April 2014

I joined the company as a management trainee, which was a two-year course. During this course I earned my HND in Business and Management Studies. At the end of the scheme, I was promoted to the job of Assistant Branch Manager. My roles in this job were to run the day-to-day operations of the branch, which included working with suppliers, daily stock management, stock control, branch and stock organisation, transport management, administrative tasks etc. I also dealt with customer issues, complaints and orders and created strong relationships with my customers to boost satisfaction levels and meet sales targets. I enjoyed getting to know my customers and going the extra mile for them. I managed a small team; I was the youngest team member but due to hard work I earned the respect and confidence of my colleagues who I keep in touch with today. I took the opportunity to gain extra qualifications in things such as first aid and forklift driving, this is an attitude that I have continued as I am always open to expanding my knowledge and improving myself.